The next step is that I also want to support sign in on this form and I'll do this in a very simple way,
I'll add another button here below my form and on this button, I'll say switch to let's say sign in, the
button type can be danger to make it red so that it looks like this
and now I want to manage this state here in my state,
in this component I'll name the property I'll add to my state isSignUp
and initially it's true, we should be in sign up mode initially but whenever this button is clicked,
I'll execute a switchAuthModeHandler
and there I simply want to call this.setState in its function form,
so I receive the previous state and in that function, I return the object which gets merged with the
old state and there I'll set
isSignUp equal to what previous state
isSignUp was not,
so I'll add an exclamation mark in front of previous state isSign so that I basically switch the values.
Now to also reflect this on UI,
I'll overwrite this hardcoded caption here and I'll not switch to sign in but I'll check if this state
isSignUp,
if it is then I'll output a string sign in because we want to switch to sign in if the current state
isSignUp and otherwise, I'll switch to sign up like this.
With that in place, I'll distribute this over a new line because I want to add the clicked property the
button knows, you can check the button component to see that props.clicked is called when onClick is
registered on the native button.
So there on clicked,
I now when to execute my auth method
handler, switchAuthMethodHandler. With that if I save this, now we can switch between the two methods,
of course this doesn't do anything, for this to have any effect
we need to do something different on the submit handler.
We always call onAuth where in the end, we always execute this auth action
and that actually is fine, I just expect to get a third argument here,
that's the method for example if it's sign up or sign in and I will simply send the request to different
URLs for different methods.
So I can set a default URL which could be the sign up URL here,
let me copy that entire URL and store it in a string here
but if method, if that is not or let's not name it method, in the end it signals if it's sign up so I'll
name it isSign here too
and if this is not sign up mode, then the URL should be different and which URL that is can
be seen in the documentation. Here in sign in with email and password,
we now grab this URL which is essentially the same,
just this part
here, the verify password,
that's different.
If we have a look at our code, there we have that URL and we have sign up new user, now for authenticating
it's the same URL with verify password.
Nonetheless I'll copy the exact same URL here, add it here
and add the key at the end
but now this URL points to verify password.
With that, we got the URL adjusted to our mode and now we use that URL here in the post
request.
The last step is to pass that URL on to the auth action creator or not
the URL, the sign up mode
I should say.
So let's go back to the auth container
and there, you will see that of course at the bottom where we call onAuth, I expect to get e-mail and
password,
I now also want to get the isSignUp information here and I will pass it on as a third argument to
the auth action creator, isSignUp is information I can pass when I call this property in my submit handler
here onAuth because I of course store this in my state of this container. So I can access this state
isSignUp and pass that information on.
With that if we save all files and we go back to our application, we see that by default if I use the
same e-mail address as before, we should get an error because that e-mail address is already in use.
We can confirm this in redux if we check authFail,
we have a look at the action,
the error we pass on there if we switch this to the right,
the error we pass on and the response has a data where it clearly says e-mail exists.
However if I switch to sign in and I submit, we see success and we get back auth data with the token and
and so on because we successfully do sign in here. So we can switch,
this is all working, with that
the next step is of course to store that token so that we can also use it in the future.