In the last lecture, we made sure that we update the UI depending on our authentication state
and of course the same logic we used there can be used anywhere in your application if you need to change
something depending on the auth state,
we'll also do that in one of the next lectures
but for now, I want to make sure that the logout link works
Now logout leads to
/logout obviously
and I want to do something upon a logout,
I want to clear my token and we do have an action for that, if we check the store actions folder auth,
there we do have that logout action creator
so I want to dispatch that and I then of course also want to redirect,
for example if we click logout, I always want to redirect back to the starting page so that if we
were on orders, we're not staying there because we're not authenticated anymore,
so that's the idea, redirect and dispatch this logout action.
Now there are different ways you can achieve this,
one possibility would be to go to your navigation items here and make sure that you create a separate
kind of navigation item which isn't a link but actually a button
and then you could register some action prop which in the end is a link to a method you want to call to
dispatch,
that would be a way to handle this situation.
I want to show you this way with linking to a page which then just redirects and logs you out,
so what I'll do is I'll go to my containers folder and in the auth folder, I'll add a new subfolder, logout
there I'll add a logout.js file.
This will be a class based component so I'll import react and component from react and I'll create a class
which I'll name logout which extends the component, of course.
Now there I'll have my render method
and there I will return some jsx
and of course I'll export this logout class as the default.
Now I want to do two things,
dispatch that action and redirect,
let's start with dispatching the action. Here
I will add a new const, mapDispatchToProps,
this should hold a function where we get the dispatch function as an argument
and where I'll return this well-known javascript object mapping props to dispatch methods.
So here, I'll add onLogout prop and this will hold a function which in the end calls dispatch and which
now should well
be able to dispatch that action from my action creators file.
So I'll import everything as actions from
and now I go up to the top, into the store folders, into the actions folders to the index.js file as in all
my other containers too so that here what I can do is I can call actions and then there I need to log
out action.
So to be able to access it, I first of all need to export it in that index.js file in the actions
folder there,
right now I only export auth
I will now also export logout from the auth file in there. With that exported here
too, I can go back to the logout container and call actions logout here as a function.
So this is the onLogout prop which I can call as a function to dispatch this action and I want to do
this right at the start
when we enter this page.
So here what I can do is I can add componentDidMount and I can then call this.props.onLogout and
this will then be the first thing I do when rendering this component.
Then as I said, I also want to redirect
and now we have two different ways of doing that,
one would be to forward the props of this component which will be loaded via the router,
so therefore we could forward this props history and on that history object of the router,
we would have the push method.
Now what I want to do instead is I want to redirect declaratively,
So I'll import redirect, the redirect component from react-router-dom,
that's a very elegant way of redirecting.
And then the only thing I return as part of this component is that redirect component here which means
whenever this container is loaded, it just redirects me, of course a very easy way of redirecting the user.
I then want to redirect to just slash, let's say
and with that, I now got a logic to well instantly redirect me. So with that, the only thing that's left to
do is make sure that the logout container gets loaded for /logout,
I do this in my app.js file on the root level where I have all my routes,
I'll simply add one more route where I load /logout, like this and there I don't want to load
the auth component, instead here,
I want to load the logout component which can be found in the auth folder but there in the logout subfolder
and there of course, in the logout file and now logout is what I assign to this route. With that if I save this,
let's go back to the application and see if this all works as it should.
It doesn't
and this makes sense because if I have a look at my logout container, there's one thing I forgot. I do have
mapDispatchToProps but I don't call connect
so this prop is actually not available yet.
That's of course a common gotcha
so let's quickly import connect from react-redux, like this and wrap our logout function with it
or with the function it returns to be precise.
So let's pass mapDispatchToProps,
the first argument therefore should be null and then we wrap the logout container with the result
of the connect function call,
now this prop should be available.
It is,
we load this app correctly.
Let's go to authenticate and quickly sign in with our user here, switch to sign in and submit, we are
authenticated.
Now let's go to orders, that works and now let's click onLogout and you see we are immediately redirected
and we do see auth logout here
so this action was dispatched,
that's great.
Now with that implemented, I want to work more on the UI, I want to make sure we don't even see the orders
button if we're not authenticated and I want to make sure that when we build a burger, that this
is available when we're not authenticated but that the order now button actually is a sign up to order or
or something like this button
when we are not authenticated.
So let's continue with that in the next lectures.