So we want to make sure that when we build a burger and are redirected to the sign up page because
we weren't authenticated, that we are then redirected to the checkout page from the authenticate page so that
we can continue with the burger
checkout. This is actually not that difficult,
there are multiple ways of doing that.
One way would be to simply store some information in your redux store, store the information if we're currently
building a burger and reset that whenever the user visits to burger builder page.
We're kind of storing this already whenever in our actions or in the reducer in the burger builder
reducer, whenever setIngredients is caught,
that means the user visited the burger builder, setIngredients
of course resets all ingredients by setting them into the reloaded state and therefore it is easy to
add a new property to our burger builder store which would be something like building and that is false
initially.
Now we can set this building property to true whenever we add or remove an ingredient, so whenever we
work on the burger.
Let's do that, in addIngredient
we already update our state with ingredients and the total price,
let's now also update the building state to true here,
let's do the same for this scenario here,
removeIngredient.
Now when setIngredients is called though, I want to set building to false because we just reloaded the
page, we're starting from scratch we're not building yet.
With this new building prop added to the burger builder slice of the state, we can go to our auth page
and there where we redirect the user after signing in,
we should have two different redirects, one to just slash and one to the checkout page depending on
where we need to go.
Now a more dynamic approach if you need to support different URLs would be to store the URL in your
redux store, so the path where you want to go to in your redux store so that you can dynamically replace it here
or to pass that path as query params for routing, you also learned how to pass and parse query params
in this course.
Let's do the half measure and store the path in the redux store even though in our app we only have
one path.
So in the auth reducer because I think it belongs to the auth slice of our state, it is in the end what
we want to do after authenticating,
I'll add an auth redirect path
prop and by default, that's just a string holding a slash to redirect to the root page.
However we should be able to change this, for that I
first of all need to register a new action,
so I'll go to my auth actions file or the action types first and there I'll export a new const, SET_AUTH_REDIRECT_PATH
with an equal identifier like this
and I need to add a new action in my auth, the action
creator file now,
I'll add it at the bottom here but the position doesn't matter,
this will be a function of course and it's the setAuthRedirectPath action creator, it will receive an
argument,
the path we want to set and then we want to return the action which should be dispatched here.
Now that action should of course be of the type we just created
so the type is imported from action types and there it's this SET_AUTH_REDIRECT_PATH and I'll pass a payload,
another property on this object,
the path property which holds the path we receive as an argument.
Let's handle this action in the auth reducer
now, there I'll add a new function above my reducer function to keep the pattern of having a lean
switch case statement,
it'll be called setAuthRedirectPath and there I'll receive state and action of course
and I want to return an updated state with updateObject and I will update this authRedirectPath here,
this property of my state slice. So authRedirectPath will then be set to action path, the path property
on the action because that is what we'll dispatch here,
there will be a path property in our action when it is dispatched.
With that, we have our reducer function prepared,
let's now add a case for it.
So add a new case in that switch case statement in the auth reducer where I'll listen to actionTypes.SET_AUTH_
REDIRECT_PATH and then return the updated path
when this function gets executed.
So now we have a way to set that path,
now this set of redirect action we added in the auth action creator file of course needs to be dispatched
whenever we want to adjust the path. For that,
first of all let's add it to the index.js file to make it available in other files through export here
and then let's have a look at where we need to change the path. Obviously in the burger builder, here
we are redirecting to auth
and before I do this, I want to change the redirect path away from that auth page.
So I'll go down to the bottom, to mapDispatchToProps and I'll add a new function here which
is
onSetRedirectPath or onSetAuthRedirectPath to be very clear about what this does and this function will
dispatch actions.setAuthRedirectPath.
Now to this action creator, we need to pass the path and I expect to get this as an input here
so I'll pass it on to the action creator,
now we can use this prop to dispatch this action and I want to do this right before we actually redirect
to the auth page,
we could also do it thereafter though, I'll call this.props.onSetAuthRedirectPath and set it to
/checkout because this is where the user should go thereafter.
So now with that, we got our redirect path set up,
we also want to set the redirect path to / if the user clicked on the authenticate button in our navigation
though
and this is something we can do in the auth container itself.
Now we do reach this auth container by pushing it with this push function here,
so by loading it as a route and therefore, if we dispatch the onSetAuthRedirectPath in there,
this will always be set whenever we go to the auth page.
However keep in mind that we have one additional piece of information in our store, in the burger builder
slice,
we have that building information here, that building information is very useful to us of course, we can
use it in the auth container to change the redirect path back if we think that the user is actually not
building a burger anymore, so we can simply go to componentDidMount in this auth container, componentDidMount
and there I want to dispatch this set redirect path too
if we are not building a burger, otherwise this path is probably set up correctly.
So I need to get two pieces of information, I need to get the information if we are building a burger,
so building burger could be the prop name and I reach out to state, then to the burger builder slice,
if you're not sure about the name of the slice,
always check your index.js file,
there you are combining your reducer and it's this property you are looking for.
So burger builder is our slice name and there, we got this building prop.
Additionally we got the authRedirectPath here,
that's coming from state.auth
and now if you have a look at the auth reducer there, we can see it's that authRedirectPath property,
so that is what I want to bind to my prop here in mapStateToProps and that also I need to be able
to dispatch a change in the redirect path. So add a prop here on setAuthRedirectPath and set this equal
to a function where we dispatch actions setAuthRedirectPath and now we could receive the path as
an argument to this function here and pass it on
or we just hard code / in here because if I call this action from within that component, I always
want to reset it back to its basic form.
So with that, I can now go into my function and adjust it as required,
here where I check if we are authenticated, I'll actually return different redirects,
I will bind this too to my dynamic property authRedirectPath which is bound to the path stored in my
redux store.
So authRedirectPath is the prop name
so here, I'll bind this.props.authRedirectPath.
Now the only thing I have to do is I have to make sure that I actually reset the path if we reach
this page whilst not building a burger
and that is what we do in componentDidMount. Here I'll check if this.props.buildingBurger is true
or to be precise, if it is not true
and if this.props.authRedirectPath is unequal to a / because that means we're trying to redirect
to checkout
even though we're not building a burger. In this case I want to call on setAuthRedirectPath
and I don't need to pass an argument here because we already set this up to always pass / at the
bottom of
our component to the action creator here,
so now we reset the path whenever we reach the auth page without building a burger.
Well there was a lot of work,
let's see if that works.
Back in our burger builder, let's first of all reload the app
so we're not authenticated and
let's go to the authenticate page and log in.
We should be redirected to the root page
now, switch to sign in, submit, this works.
Now let's try again, let's log out,
build a burger,
very delicious one with just salad oh
I can almost taste it.
Let's click sign up to order,
we go to authenticate,
let's now sign in,
we should now reach checkout and we do, we can check the burger out here.
Let's now also see if the burger is still set up correctly and we can't just inspect our state to confirm
this in the burger builder slice,
we still got the ingredients there and the price
so we would store the correct burger on our backend.
Finally let's log out, build a burger and click on sign up to order,
now let's not sign iN but go back to burger builder,
the burger is reset, let's inspect our state real quick now. We see that in the auth slice, authRedirectPath
is still /checkout.
Let's go back to authenticate now
and now this throws an error, it's not a function.
It makes sense,
this should be this.props.onSetAuthRedirectPath, we're of course accessing this on our props because
we set it through mapDispatchToProps. With that,
fix this back, go back.
So let's try again back to the burger builder, build a burger,
click on sign up to order,
don't sign in,
go back to burger builder and go back to authenticate
and now we see setAuthRedirect was dispatched and it overwrote the redirect path.
So now if we sign in, we shouldn't reach checkout even though the last thing we did was build a burger
but now we should reach the front page again.
So that's all working fine now,
we do respect the choice of the user and we do forward him to the page which makes the most sense.
A lot was acheived with that,
let's next work on the issue in quotation marks that if we are logged in and we reload the page, we are
logged out,
let's see what we can do about that in the next lecture.