So we added a lot of functionality to our app,
we still have the behavior that if we are logged in and we reload the page, the login state is lost.
The reason for this is that when we refresh the page, we download the single page application again, we
download the javascript again, it gets executed again,
it's a totally new application when we look at it like this.
Therefore our state stored in redux which is in the end just stored in javascript is of course lost.
So we need it to persist our login state across our sessions
and this requires a browser API
we can use, local storage.
Now let's see how we can utilize local storage in this lecture.
I'll go to my auth action creator, here where we do successfully login and dispatch authSuccess,
there we also pass on the token and it would make sense to also store that token in our browser
local storage then. The local storage API is baked into the browser so we can easily use it,
we can either use it here in our auth action creator or in authSuccess before we dispatch an action.
There we could run some additional code,
we get the token here but I don't want to work with just the token,
I also want to work with the expire, expiration time.
So what I'll do is I'll work or I'll set the token here in my auth action creator where we dispatch authSuccess
and authTimeout. There, I'll also access local storage just like that, it's built into javascript and
we can call setItem on it to store an item in the local storage, the item I want to store is my token
let's say
and that's just the key by which we can fetch it.
The second argument to setItem is the actual item
and this is response data ID token, extracted from our response just as we do it here.
Now that's nice but the token alone won't be that useful if we fetch it in the future,
we also need to know when it expires.
So I'll store something else, setItem and I could store expiresIn but that's just the amount of
seconds until it's invalid,
that won't tell us much the next time we fetch this from local storage because the number of course
won't update.
So instead we should store the expiration date, so expiration date and the value should be the expiration
date,
now I'm going to calculate this and store it in a separate constant,
expirationDate can be calculated as new date which gives us the current date plus the expiration time,
so response data expires in times 1000 because javascript time works in milliseconds and the time we
got was in seconds
but just like that it won't work, instead on the new date we generated, we have to extract getTime,
it's a function, it gives us the current time of the date and now this gives us the expiration time
but to turn this into a date object again, we have to wrap all of that with new date.
So new date without arguments like here gives us the current date, new date with arguments
gives us a date with the date we passed as an argument,
so here this will be the current date plus 10 seconds, plus expiry time in seconds.
So this is how that works,
now we can store expiration date in our local storage too whenever we acquire a token, before we continue
let's see if that works.
Let's go back to our browser,
click on authenticate, switch to sign in and let's authenticate here, submit and we can inspect our local
storage in the Chrome browser dev tools by going to the application tab there.
On the application tab, you will find some storage information and you can click on local storage and
expand it and click on your domain,
you'll see the two fields
we set, token and expiration date which is your local date time which makes sense for that given user
where you have your well date
where this is going to expire
and I can say that for me, this date is true here.
So this is our expiration date,
we can now take advantage of these two fields to check them whenever our application loads, to log the
user in if we got a token
and if it's still valid, so if we haven't passed the expiration date yet.
Otherwise we want to clean this up,
we want to clean this up with the logout dispatch action.
So in the auth file in the actions folder where we have logout, there
I also want to access local storage and I simply want to remove my two items here.
So I want to remove the token and I also want to remove the expiration time because both is not needed
anymore and shouldn't be stored any more,
we aren't loged in anymore so the token will not be valid in the future.
So now let's fetch the token when we login,
where can we check this?
Well we should check it when the application loads,
so for example in app.js this is the root component of our app and it's always loaded, no matter which
route we visit
so therefore this makes for a great app to check our authentication status. For checking this,
we will need a new action
so let's go to the auth file in the actions folder and there, I essentially want to dispatch authSuccess
whenever we are logged in
but also execute or dispatch checkAuthTimeout and pass the expiration in amount to still have that
functionality going. For that, I'll create a new action creator in the auth.js file, I'll name it
authCheckState
for example, I won't receive any arguments here but I will return a function here so that I can dispatch
multiple actions,
I won't run asynchronous code but I still want to dispatch multiple actions from within this action
and then here, I want to get my token from local storage with getItem token and I want to get my expiration
time.
Now before I do that, if token is null so if we can't validate this to be true-ish, then I just want to
return in the end because I don't need to do anything here, I don't need to dispatch anything,
I could dispatch the logout function but that also shouldn't be required
but still, I will call dispatch logout like this.
So in the else case that we got a token, I'll also fetch the expiration time and store it in a constant expirationTime,
I'll reach out to local storage and get my item expirationTime was the identifier we used for
storing it here,
expirationDate
so let's fix this expirationDate here,
we should also remove expirationDate appeared in the logout action creator though,
so expirationDate all over the place. With that updated,
we got it stored here in a constant, we got the token stored in a constant,
now we can use both pieces of information. And I want to dispatch my authSuccess action creator because
I know that we are logged in,
however I only want to do this if we haven't passed the expiration date.
So what I'll do is I'll first of all wrap this with new date because what we retrieve from local storage
will be a string but with new date we can convert it into a date object and then I'll check if expirationDate
is actually greater than new date which is
now, if that's the case then I don't want to login.
So in this case, I also want to dispatch logout, else and of course you could restructure this a bit to have
less nested if else statements but here I'll leave it like this. Else
I know the expiration date is still in the future,
now I want to dispatch authSuccess, pass on my token and I need the user id here.
Now for that I'll need to fetch it,
of course we could also simply store it in local storage and that wouldn't be wrong,
you can however also send the request to the firebase auth API to get it from there,
if you have a look at the firebase auth API documentation, there you'll see that you can get user data
by sending a request to this endpoint with your API key and the ID token as a body payload because this
is a post request even though it's called get user data,
it's a bit strange.
So this would be a way to get the user data, in the response you would have a users object which actually
is an array and in the first element of the array, you would have your user and local ID would be the user
ID,
so this is how you could fetch it from the server,
I however will simply store it in local storage because it's a bit easier here.
So for that, let's make sure that we also store this in our auth action creator
once we got the response, there I'll reach out to local storage
set our item, user ID and store response data local ID is the user id there and also remove that of course
if we logout, so remove user ID and with that, we can fetch it
in our case here. We can fetch a user ID if we are logged in,
so here const user ID will be local storage, get item user ID and now I can pass this as a second argument
to authSuccess.
Now the last thing I want to do is I also want to dispatch this other action, checkAuthTimeout
and there I need to pass an argument which is the amounts of seconds, the amount of seconds until we should
be logged out,
expirationDate however of course is the time when we are logged out
not the amount of seconds.
What we can do though is we can simply pass expirationDate, get seconds minus new date get seconds.
So this is simply passing the difference between the future date and how many seconds these are,
so the future date in seconds that's a big number
and the current date in seconds and the difference of course is the expiry date, the expiry time in
seconds I mean.
So with that we're dispatching everything here in authCheckState,
so this is a pure utility action creator which dispatches a couple of other actions depending on our
current state.
And with that, we can dispatch authCheckState to successfully automatically log the user in if we have
a valid token.
Let's see if this works by going to the app.js container
and there I first of all need to import connect to be able to dispatch anything from this container,
so let's import connect from react-redux
and then here at the bottom before I export the app, I'll create map state, excuse me, mapDispatchToProps, receive
that dispatch function and there return my javascript object where I do map my props. Here I'll add the
onTryAutoSignUp prop for example and I'll dispatch this one action we just created which I therefore
also need to export in the index.js file in my actions folder.
So there I'll add my check or my authCheckState argument, my authCheckState action creator we created
a second ago and that is the action I want to dispatch in the app container,
so here I'll reach out to my actions which I
first of all need to import at the top
so import everything as actions from that actions file in the store actions index file here,
so this actions object contains all the exported action creators.
So here we can then reach out to actions.authCheckState, like this,
now we just have to connect our container
so connect pass
mapDispatchToProps and pass null for mapStateToProps because we're not mapping any state
to props here.
And now let's execute this
for example in componentDidMount, there let's call this.props.onTryAutoSignUp. With that if we save
everything,
let's try this out.
Now if we are on that page and click on authenticate, you'll see that doesn't work,
we see in the redux dev tools that authLogout was dispatched which makes a lot of sense because it
means that our onTryAutoSignUp was dispatched and that we made it into this authCheckState action
creator therefore
but then we didn't find a token and there indeed isn't one in my local storage right now
and therefore logout was dispatched.
However why can't we reach authenticate now,
let's have a look at this in the next lecture.