Now let's work on our orders,
let's make sure we only see orders of our user and for that of course, we
first of all need to make sure that when we place an order, we attach the user id. Thankfully the user ID
is stored in our auth slice of the state here, user ID here.
So we're storing that already
so we only need to make sure that we also take advantage of this when we place an order.
So in our orders action creators when we purchase a burger, we want to pass the user id onto the backend
so it should be part of the order data, I'd say.
That however is set in our contact data container, there in the order handler, we in the end dispatch
onOrderBurger,
we call this function which dispatches the action and there, we set up our order data.
This is where I
also want to add the user ID.
Now since we store that in our redux store,
that's super easy to do,
we can just get it from there.
So in mapStateToProps in the contact data container, I'll add a user id prop and reach out to
state.auth.userID, like this.
Now we can use that for prop anywhere in this component,
for example when we do submit an order, so in the order handler, here where we set up the order, there we can
simply add another property and that is our user ID property which is this.props.userID, this newly
mapped prop
and that should be all. With that,
if I now place an order let's quickly try this out,
let's order this delicious burger, continue and fill this out,
so once this is filled out here and we click order,
this all seems to work.
Let's now have a look at our backend
the order was added and there, we see that in the, not in the order data but here on the main element
itself,
we have user ID which is our user ID.
So now that order is mapped to our user.
Now of course, we also want to make sure that when we visit orders, we only see orders of that user.
Now there are two ways of checking this, one is on the frontend because the data we get back from the
backend will hold this information, we can see this if we expect our state here for fetch orders success,
order, this orders array,
the last order which is the most recent one has this user id property
so we could check if that user ID matches the ID of the logged in user. But we would still fetch all orders
and that's a potential security issue because if anyone inspects our javascript code, he could see orders
which aren't meant for him.
So a better way is to just fetch the orders we need from the backend in the first place and we can
do that easily with firebase, of course for your own API you need some way of passing that user ID to
the backend or use that token you pass along anyways to only fetch data for a given user. When using
firebase,
you can easily filter data by going back to your async order action creator file and there where we
have fetch orders, we already passed the token, we can pass more query params here
and since I will add more, I'll actually add my new constant here and I'll name this query params and
this will just be a string where I have auth equal to token and then I'll change them,
I use query parameter with an and sign,
this will be orderBy with a capital B,
that is a query parameter understood by firebase which allows us to well order our data.
Now I don't actually want to reorder it but this also tells firebase hey you can filter by that.
So I want to order by my user ID property and now we can chain another query parameter
and that is equal to,
this always refers to the key you're ordering by.
So we can say we want to order by that user id property on our firebase data and we only want to fetch
the data where this key, user ID is equal to
and now we need to get the user ID here.
So I expect to get it,
we could of course also get it
with that get state argument we can retrieve here but I don't want to use that, instead
I expect to get the user id here as an argument and then here at my URL, I replace the current code
at the end by simply attaching my query params constant now which holds all the query params.
So let's make sure we get the user id then, to do that I need to go to the place where we execute fetch
orders or where we dispatch this action
and that of course happens in the orders container, there
this.props.onFetchOrders is used, here I now simply need to get the user id so let's add it to our props
and get it from the state, from the auth state,
there it's in a user id property as you can always check your reducer and I need to be able to dispatch
my action with that ID,
so there, I pass an additional argument and pass it onto the action creator because we just added it,
this action creator to expect this argument
and then we have to pass it on in our container code too, here
I also passed this.props.userId, like this and that should be all.
Now if we go back to our application and we go back to orders, I actually get an error because I have
a tiny syntax error in our orders action creator, orderBy, the value or the property name by which you
want to order,
it should be enclosed in quotation marks, in double quotation marks.
Now that's not the only change though,
the value we're passing here, if it's a string and user ID is a string also needs to be wrapped with double
quotation marks,
so let's add one in front of our variable and then one thereafter
between the single quotation marks because it's still text.
With that we're done, we've done almost everything
but we also need to prepare it on the backend, here in firebase and that's just firebase specific because
we well happen to use firebase here, if you want to be able to filter data,
we have to adjust our rules to make a certain field indexable so that firebase can search through it.
This is done in your rules tap on the database, there
we can simply go to orders and we have read and write there and
now we add another rule, .indexOn and it's of course very important that you write this correctly,
with dot at the beginning and a capital O,
and now you can add an array of all the fields you want to make searchable, here
it's only user ID though.
Now let's publish that
and now with that in place and our code here updated too and everything saved, if go back to the burger
and we are logged in and we go to orders,
we see only one order now and that should be our order.
Let's confirm by creating the bacon bomb burger here, salad always important,
so let's order this now.
If I click order and now go to orders,
we see that here too.
So now we only get the data and we have no chance of accessing data that doesn't belong to our user.
Now this example is of course only showing us with firebase but on your own backend, you probably have
your own filtering logic, either returning only user related data from the server
anyways by checking the token you pass along or by also giving you some query functionality as we
used it here.