In the last lecture we had a look at react native, an amazing library and I can only recommend you
to dive into it.
Now let's move back to reactjs
though and let's have a look at Material-UI. Material-UI is another library
you can use together with react
but unlike nextjs or Gatsbyjs, it's not building up on react,
it's a component library instead and it's not the only one.
There are a lot of component libraries you can import into your react project
and as the name suggests, component libraries are libraries that give you pre-built and pre-styled
components. You can still write your own ones
but for example Material-UI gives you beautiful nice working material design components.
If you go on their website, make sure to click on that yeah
version one is coming link if it's still showing up for you at the top of the page.
There on their web page, you can click on component demos and actually see the many components you
can easily import and use in your projects,
you can always find the source code for a given demo
if you click on that source code icon here on the top right corner of the example and then you see what
you need to import from that library,
granted that you have it installed,
you'll learn how to install it on the Getting Started link and then you can quickly add nicely styled and
looking components without having to build them on your own.
That's a powerful feature if you are building very big applications where you want to have a uniform
look, you can of course sketch out and build all the core components on your own
but if you know that you want to follow the material look, definitely have a look at Material-UI.
.
And if you want another look,
have a look at other popular component libraries, like for example bootstrap react.
If you search for bootstrap react, you should find that react bootstrap library here where you can
also find components that take the bootstrap styling but work nicely in react and are easily integrated
into react apps.
So that's the general thing I want to bring to you with this lecture,
dive into component libraries,
be aware that they exist and consider them for your next projects
if you need uniform styling,
don't want to build all these components on your own and just want to have nice react components as
you would have build them on your own
but just ready to be dropped in into your own react application.