In the last lecture we installed some production dependencies, dependencies we'll need for the core of
our application,
now I want to start working on the webpack config.
We already installed the webpack tool,
here's the dependency in the package.json
file and I said that I will manage the workflow through the scripts we have here which we
then can run with npm run and then the script name or in the case of the special script, npm start we
can just type npm start, and the start script should be the one launching the development server.
So I want to add a new script to the scripts section which is called start and on the right side of the
colon, in the double quotation marks which you need to use since this file uses the json format, here
I want to simply execute webpack-dev-server,
make sure to not mistype,
this has to be the name of this package which simply exposes a function you execute with this call.
So this will spin up the dev server,
however the dev server out of the box won't work,
we need to configure it and to configure it, I'll add a new file next to the package.json file,
I'll name it webpack.config.js
this is a special file name,
make sure to name it exactly like this webpack.config.js. Webpack will automatically look
for this file when executing either webpack or webpack-dev-server as we do here, so it will automatically
take this file into account,
therefore you have to get the naming right. Now
in this file,
I'll set up my development workflow.
We'll later create a separate file for the production workflow because there, we will differ in some aspects,
we will apply some extra optimizations and so on.
So in the webpack.config.js file, I'll now set up my webpack workflow
and for that, we need to export something here which webpack will then use,
we do this with the node export format by writing module.exports and we then set this equal to a javascript
object.
So this is the syntax webpack understands to read in the config we now specify in this javascript object
and I did mention the four important aspects of that configuration earlier on a slide,
let's start with the entry point. Here we define where the journey starts for webpack and we want to point
to our index.js file here.
So here I'll point to ./source index.js,
this tells webpack that it should look at this file first and then analyze the dependencies of that
file which are all the imports
and then it is able to do something with these imports.
However to be able to handle css or any other non javascript file, we need to give webpack some
extra set up,
we need to do this for javascript files too though since we use jsx which is not native javascript
and since we use next generation javascript features too,
we also import images and stuff like that
so that's all the stuff we have to handle with loaders later. Before we do that,
I'll add one additional configuration,
it's called dev tool and here we can define which kind of source maps, if any webpack should generate
and I'll use cheap-module-eval-source-map here.
Now that's super confusing long term, in the end it is the best kind of source maps you can generate for the
development,
very detailed, good performance,
so this is what you should use here to get source maps which allow you to easily debug your original
code in the browser.
So with that we get the entry
let's now also define the output so the output key and here I want to create a new folder with a file,
output is not just a string, it's an object and in that object we configured the path,
so where this should be stored,
the file name,
so where our or how our file should be named
and the public path,
that's important for webpack to know where our files are put to
and if that then is the root folder of the server in the end or if it's a nested folder.
So here it should be the root folder so public path is just an empty string
which means you store the files in a specific folder and you don't need to adjust any imports or adjust
for anything,
the file structure, the folder structure will be the folder structure as we deployed
in the end. More important is the file name, here
that's a string too,
we define what the file should be named and I want to name it
bundle.js,
it's a convention to use bundle.js just because it is a bundled javascript in the end.
Now you might wonder what happens to css images,
this will be handled differently by certain loaders we add and the loaders will define where the css
or image code is put,
so this only affects javascript
therefore it's bundle.js.
Now the path is also important,
where should the assets be stored?
And there I will actually import a node module which is called path which I do with the node import
style where I require the path module.
Now we didn't install this with npm install but it is a default node module,
so since we have node installed we can also pull this in. The path object here has a resolve method which
allows us to generate an absolute path in the end, here
we can pass a special variable which we have available in node systems and webpack will use node
behind the scenes,
so it will have access to that variable,
it's __dirname and it refers to the directory
this is running and then the second argument to resolve is the folder where we want to create it and
resolve will then create an absolute path taking the full path to the current folder on our operating
system and appending dist,
so it will in the end output a file in the dist folder which doesn't exist yet which it will create
instead which is named bundle.js,
this is the output of this operation.
Now that is the base set up here,
this doesn't transform any files or anything like that though
so these are all things I'll take care about in the next lectures.