Now in the last lecture we started to really set up a saga
workflow that makes more sense where we listen to certain actions and then simply execute a saga
which then handles the side effects that are relevant for this action.
Now one important note, I did import takeEvery which sets up our listener from redux saga,
this actually should be redux saga/effects, just a little side note, that's important.
Now with that, let's move on and let's make sure that we actually handle all side effects in our sagas.
So if we stick to the auth.js file for now, let's go through it from top to bottom and see what else
we should put into a saga.
Now auth start doesn't need a saga,
it's action creator which just returns an action,
so it's a pure action creator, no side effects inside of it.
The same is true for auth success and for auth fail,
all these action creators really just will create actions.
We already cleaned up logout,
there is one thing we could do though,
I really put this action here,
now we can definitely use this approach where we just put an object, we could even get rid of all action
creators
now that we use sagas but we could also say that we want to use action creators to have a reliable way
of well, creating our actions and therefore, we should probably also use an action creator here in our saga
instead of hard coding the action object in here.
So I will actually create a new action creator in the auth.js file and I'll name it logoutSucceed,
this will be a function and in here, I will now return the object I hardcoded into the saga,
so this action here, I'll cut it from there and return it in logoutSucceed instead,
you could also name it didLogout or whatever you want. Now this constant here in my action file should
therefore also be exported, which it is so that I can use it
and now in my auth.js
file, in the saga file, I'll import everything as actions from actions index,
right now if we check the index.js file in the actions folder where I now should store, I should
add it to the export here from the auth file,
so here it's logoutSucceed.
So now in my auth.js file in the sagas folder, I can now put actions logoutSucceed and simply execute
this action creator here.
So now with that, I have a consistent approach of using action creators and I no longer need to import
action types in here because I don't hardcode my action in here.
But we wanted to look for other actions to replace with sagas,
right?
So we did it for logout,
now checkAuthTimeout
also is causing some side effects here.
We actually have some asynchronous code in here, setting a timer where we dispatch an action every
time, well the timer finishes,
this is something we definitely want to do in a saga instead
so let's do that.
I'll head over to auth.js in the sagas folder and I'll
first of all create a new generator function,
so a function with a star after the function keyword.
Now we named the auth action creator here
checkAuthTimeout,
so in our saga file we could name it checkAuthTimeoutSaga, we could also name it timedOutLogoutSaga,
whatever you like,
I'll stick to this name.
There I'll also get the action and now in here, in this function I want to execute kind of the same code
I executed in my action creator where I had a timeout and an expiration time and where I then also dispatched
an action so
let's first of all copy it over into our generator
but this is not really how we want to execute it. In a generator, we'll instead rewrite it
and first of all, I can import a helper function, not from redux saga effects but from redux saga,
just like that and that helper function here is called delay
and as you might guess, it delays the execution of the next step.
So what I do is I yield delay and I enter the amount of time I want to delay the execution.
Now the expiration time is not an argument we get here, we get an action here instead but I simply assume
that this action will have the expiration time field and I will delay the continued execution for this
amount of time.
Now with that, what we can do is we pause the execution here and once we're done,
once this succeeds, I really want to log the user out, so here I will yield put and simply execute
actions, not to be confused with our argument here,
actions refers to the actions we import, execute actions logout which will initiate the logout and
actually lead to this saga being executed after a while.
So now we can remove this other code here and this is how we would write our wait for the token to expire
and then logout action code in a saga style.
Now in auth.js, checkAuthTimeout here is now no longer an action creator where I really want to execute
my code here, instead here, I simply just want to dispatch an action which leads to this saga generator
here being started.
So for that I'll add a new action type, I'll export a constant in there which I'll name authCheckTimeout,
use this a string identifier here too and now, I simply want to dispatch this action here
so type, action types authCheckLogout and also important, pass on the expiration time because I'm trying
to extract that in my saga.
So now with that, we got our checkAuthTimeout function running, now to see if that really works,
I'm temporarily replacing the real expiration time with 10 to see if that works, before we can see
if anything works though, we need to go to the index.js file and thus far, I'm only listening to the
auth initiate logout action type.
Now we got a new saga and a new action type so let's import both,
I'll now also import the checkAuthTimeoutSaga from the auth file and I'll yield another action type
here,
takeEvery action types authCheckTimeout and then execute my checkAuthTimeoutSaga.
Now before testing it, let's fix one tiny mistake I just spotted, when I put an action to be executed
after the expiration time,
that of course is referring to the action creator and therefore I should execute it as a function to really put
the action this action creator creates.
Now with that, let's go back to our application and let's try this out, let's first of all reload the application,
we see auth initiate logout because it tries to auto sign us in which fails,
so let's now really sign in and the expected result would be that we're signed out really fast thereafter
because we have such a short expiration time and indeed, we can see that here we are successfully signed
in,
we get a token then we set authCheckTimeout and pretty much immediately after it because we only have
a time span of 10 milliseconds, auth initiate logout is called and thereafter of course, auth logout due
to our saga.
So this is now all running correctly,
you'll also see that these yields of takeEvery seem to be executed right after each other
so it's not like we wait for this action here to occur
for this to run, actually this becomes even clearer if I switch the position because this action auth
initiate logout will appear right at the start when it tries to auto sign us in
and still, it will also successfully listen to that and not wait for this to occur before it sets up
this listener.
I can prove this by simply reloading the page and you'll see still auth initiate logout and auth logout
is executed in the authCheckLogout,
did no query yet.
So with that we get this set up,
now in the auth.js file in the actions folder, in our action creator for checkAuthTimeout,
I'll of course no longer use the 10 milliseconds
but the real expiration timeout to pass it on with the action
because again just remember you,
we use expiration time in our checkAuthTimeoutSaga,
we access it on our action here. So with that, let's move on and let's see what else we can put into a saga
from our action creator file.