So over the last lectures we learned a lot about redux saga,
there's always more you can learn
but here are a couple of nice things I want to share with you.
Let's start the auth.js file,
here we for example access local storage and I used yield here even though technically, this is a synchronous
code we don't need to wait for it.
Now one thing you can do here is you can use another helper method or function redux saga
provides you with,
you can import it from redux saga effects and it's called call. Call is a function which allows you to
call some function on some object, so you could rewrite this line here where we remove the item by executing
yield
call and then as a first argument, pass an array where the first element is local storage
but now don't call remove item but instead as a second element, pass that function you want to execute
on it.
So remove item, written exactly as it is down here,
now you can pass a second argument to the call function and these can be arguments you would pass
to remove item,
so in this case, the token.
Now you might wonder what the advantage of this is
after all, it's longer than before, right?
Well this actually makes your generators testable because you can easily mock this and not really execute this
code whilst you always need to execute it down there. So you can use call here all over the place to
also remove expiration date and user ID, that allows you to get rid of that.
So now we get the same effect as before but with the call function and you can use call wherever you
use some object and call something including axios of course or these local storage calls.
So I'm not replacing it everywhere but you can do it and if you want to test generators, you should do
it.
Now let me prove you that it still works by saving this
and now let's go back to the application and reload,
let's click log out and inspect our application tab and you see everything was deleted from local storage
still.
So this works now with the call function,
now there is one other thing you can do with it, in the index.js file,
here we have all our yields to set up our various watchers or our various sagas we want to execute
on different actions.
Here we can import all, another nice function, in watchAuth,
we can now yield
all and there pass an array of all the actions we want to yield and there I will now copy all these functions
here, however remove the real keyword in there,
remove that Y and replaced the semi-colons with colons, with commas
and now with that, if we save this and I reload my application, if we inspect the redux developer tools,
it'll still work as before
so all our watch related, auth related watchers are still working
but with all, they are actually run concurrently. Now here, this doesn't matter at all because when we
yielded them off each other, it didn't pause anyways because it were synchronous tasks.
But you cannot only use that here when setting up the watchers,
you can use it anywhere,
for example if you have these three calls here, you could execute them simultaneously with the all by wrapping
it.
However these also are synchronous
but if you have for example two axios requests and you want to run them simultaneously, you can use
all to do just that.
So all is another nice option if you want to run multiple generators or multiple tasks, don't have to
be generators, multiple tasks simultaneously.
Again you could use it for the other watchers too,
it's not really required here though.
One other thing I want to show, we always use takeEvery which can really be translated as this take every
action of this type and execute this saga.
Now in our application, this behavior is all right but what if you actually just wanted to have one
of this saga run at any time?
So for example if the user hammers the purchase burger button, we maybe only always want to use the
latest click,
that is why besides takeEvery,
we can also use takeLatest
and if we use that here on purchase burger, takeLatest will automatically cancel any ongoing executions
of purchaseBurgerSaga and always only execute the latest one.
So that's another nice addition which you might need from time to time to make sure that only one of these
processes here is going on at a time. With takeEvery, it will execute fetchOrdersSaga
whenever this action type is detected, with takeLatest, it won't and there is more. Here I'm on the official
page redux-saga.js.org
.
and there you can also find an API reference with all the functions it exposes.
Now this looks like a lot but you probably don't ever need most of them,
you can also dive into some advanced concepts on this documentation here or go through the basics again
in case something is unclear after going through this module. In its core,
the whole idea behind redux saga really is to make sure your action creators are lean, that you don't
run any side effects in there but that you instead handle these side effects in your sagas, that you
have one place where you have all the side effects and one place where you have all the actions and
that you don't mix that.
That's the idea, as I just mentioned,
feel free to dive deeper here in the official documentation and play around with it.
I hope that our little refactoring of the course project help you dive into redux saga and that it's
much clearer what you can use it for and that you definitely can consider it for your next project.